<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>boinor</title><link href="https://www.boinor.space/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.boinor.space/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.boinor.space/</id><updated>2024-07-23T20:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>new fork of poliastro</title><link href="https://www.boinor.space/blog/2024/07/23/new-fork-of-poliastro/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-23T20:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-23T20:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Thorsten Alteholz</name></author><id>tag:www.boinor.space,2024-07-23:/blog/2024/07/23/new-fork-of-poliastro/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear community,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when looking at recent RM-bugs to remove Debian packages from the archive,
I saw the removal request for poliastro. I became curious and didn't want 
to see this software go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I really hope to be able to revive this project again under the name boinor = BOdies IN …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear community,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when looking at recent RM-bugs to remove Debian packages from the archive,
I saw the removal request for poliastro. I became curious and didn't want 
to see this software go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I really hope to be able to revive this project again under the name boinor = BOdies IN ORbit.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="boinor"></category></entry><entry><title>Jorge Martinez steps down as maintainer of the project</title><link href="https://www.boinor.space/blog/2023/08/22/jorge-martinez-steps-down/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-22T21:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-08-22T21:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Jorge Martinez Garrido</name></author><id>tag:www.boinor.space,2023-08-22:/blog/2023/08/22/jorge-martinez-steps-down/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear community,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you that, due to professional commitments, I have made the
decision to step down from my role as a maintainer of the boinor project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than delving into the specific circumstances that led to this choice, I'd
like to take this opportunity to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear community,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to share with you that, due to professional commitments, I have made the
decision to step down from my role as a maintainer of the boinor project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than delving into the specific circumstances that led to this choice, I'd
like to take this opportunity to offer inspiration to new developers who are
considering joining the vibrant world of free and open-source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back to December 2018, shortly after the holiday season, I can vividly
recall the excitement of having &lt;a href="https://github.com/boinor/boinor/pull/491"&gt;my first pull request for
boinor&lt;/a&gt; merged. It was an
exhilarating moment, as it marked the first time in months that I truly felt my
contributions were making a meaningful impact, being valued and utilized by
others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my journey, &lt;a href="https://github.com/astrojuanlu"&gt;Juan Luis Cano Rodríguez&lt;/a&gt;,
an exceptional mentor, has provided invaluable guidance. His meticulous code
reviews have been a wellspring of insights that greatly enriched my learning
experience. I extend my heartfelt gratitude for the generous time and effort he
invested in teaching and mentoring me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My tenure with boinor not only allowed me to develop astro-related skills but
also opened doors to larger opportunities. As a recipient of the 
&lt;a href="https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/archive/2019/projects/4887352839766016"&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/a&gt;,
I had the privilege of receiving compensation for my software development
contributions, marking a significant milestone in my journey, especially as a
student at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I devoted countless nights to coding and learning, expanding my horizons beyond
the realm of astrophysics. One such passion is my fascination with Linux, a
topic that I find equally captivating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I take this step back, I encourage you all to consider embracing open-source
projects like boinor. The journey is rewarding, providing not only technical
growth but also a strong sense of community and purpose. New contributors, your
efforts can truly make a difference, just as mine did when I started on this
remarkable journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With gratitude and optimism,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jorge Martinez&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category><category term="boinor"></category></entry></feed>